Guide to the Center for Housing and Environmental Studies records, 1950-1969.
Center for Housing and Environmental Studies records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Center for Housing and Environmental Studies records, 1950-1969.
53-4-1308
Cornell University. Center for Housing and Environmental Studies. Director.
13 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Publications, Reports
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, project reports, accounts, speeches, publications, and committee records of Director Glenn H. Beyer of the Cornell Center for Housing and Environmental Studies.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, project reports, accounts, speeches, publications, and committee records of Director Glenn H. Beyer of the Cornell Center for Housing and Environmental Studies.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Beyer, Glenn H.; Cornell University--Planning.
Subjects:
Housing.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Digitized copy of "The Cornell Kitchen" can be found online here: https://ecommons.cornell.edu/handle/1813/40835
CONTAINER LIST
- "The Cornell Kitchen", 1955; DVD 1453
  "The Cornell Kitchen" was produced by the Reynolds Metal Company. It was written by Jerry Gammon; Technical Advisor: Professor Glen H. Beyer; Cinematography: Vitali V. Uzoff with Assistant Cameraman: Andrew C. Fain and directed by Vitali V. Uzoff. This film outlines efforts to improve and modernize the kitchen.
  The “original” film restored and maintained in the Reynolds Metals Company collection at the Virginia Historical Society.
- Social Science Research Center thru 1963, 1959-1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Correspondence, agenda, reports, memos.
- College Research Committee, 1965 onwards, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Memos, minutes, fund requests
- College Research Committee, January 1961 onwards, 1941-1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Memos, minutes, fund requests, pamphlets
- College Research Committee to January 1961, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Minutes
- College Research Committee, 1947-1954 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Minutes, memos, reports
- Centennial Celebration Committee, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Memos, minutes
- College Committee on Research, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Memos, minutes, reports
- College Study Commission, January 1966-December 1966, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Memos, reports, rough drafts
- University faculty Minutes and Notices to December 1966, 1961-1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Memos, minutes, resolutions
- Faculty Housing Subcommittee of the Commission on Economic Status of Faculty, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Memoranda, correspondence, reports, application forms
- University Faculty Minutes and Notices, 1961-1966 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Minutes, agenda, memos
- College Evaluation, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Memos, reports
- Building Research Institute - Committee on Research, 1961 onwards, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Reports, correspondence
- Metropolitan Fringe - Conference Minutes and Papers Presented, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Agenda, minutes, papers
- Housing Proposal as Submitted to Ford Foundation - Donald O'Connell, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Memos, correspondence
- C.U. Institute on Family Housing, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Drafts, reports
- Federal Housing Administration, 1960-1962 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Correspondence, reports
- Union Carbide Development Co. R.W.Lillie Proposed Project, 1960, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Memos
- Congoleum-Nairn Inc. Floor Covering Research, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Correspondence
- Lustron Contact, 1949, 1949, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Contract, correspondence, itemized report
- Organization of Cornell Planners - Spring Conference, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Agenda, correspondence, report
- Speeches, 1964 onwards, 1964-1968 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Speeches, agenda, speech notes, memos
- Speeches, 1960-1963, 1958-1963 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Speeches, notes, agenda
- Beyer and U.S. Senate Farm Housing Research Program, 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Correspondence, Senate testimony, Legal forms, reports, rough drafts
- Newspaper Clippings, 1958-1963 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Smithsonian Institute Symposium, February 1967, on "The Quality of Man's Environment", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Agenda, maps, pamphlets
- Conference, Caracas, Venezuela, April 1967 on "Inter-regional Seminar on Rural Housing and Community Facilities", 1967 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Home E.C. Faculty, Minutes and Notices, January 1965 onwards, 1965-1968 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Minutes, notices, agendas, reports
- Search Committee for C.J. Personius' Position, 7 July 1965 onwards, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Correspondence, memos
- College Study Committee, January 1967 - December 1968 and Organization Committee (College) (#3), 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Reports, minutes, agenda, memos
- College Study Committee, Reorganization of College, January 1969 onwards (#4), 1969 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Minutes of Meetings, Housing Research Center, 1950-1964 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Minutes, memos, agendas, reports
- Faculty Council, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Agendas, minutes, memos, reports, pamphlets
- Faculty Council II, 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Minutes, memos, reports, agenda
- Faculty Council, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Memos, minutes, M.C. volumes of "The University Community" and "The University in Transition", James A Perkind
- Faculty Council (University Faculty) III, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Reports, memos, agendas, minutes
- Faculty Council (University Faculty), January 1966 onwards, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Reports, minutes, memos, agendas
- Faculty Council (University Faculty) IV, January 1967 - May 1967, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Reports, agendas, memos, minutes, rough drafts
- Home E.C. 1960 Long Range Planning Commission, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Memos, reports, minutes, reprints
- University Long Range Planning RE: Centennial Planning Committee, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Reports
- Committee on university Professorships, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Correspondence, memos, agenda
- Home E.C. Meetings and Notices, to December 1964, 1961-1964 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Minutes, reports, memos, agendas
- BRI - Advisory Board (I), 1957-1960 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Correspondence(M.C.I.), reports, news releases, minutes, proceedings
- BRI Advisory Board (II), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Correspondence, reports, minutes, proceedings
- BRI - Advisory Board (III), 1961 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Minutes, program report, correspondence (M.C.I), reports
- BRI - 1959 Fall Conference, November 17 - 19, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Papers, M.C and M.S. correspondence, magazine articles, notes
- Semi Annual Report No 3, Building Research advisory Board, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Report
- BRI - News Releases, 1957-1961 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Newsletters, publications
- National Housing Workshop, 22 April 1964, Lincoln, Nebraska, "Socio-economic Aspects of Housing" - G.H.B, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Topeka Conference, 1964, "Human Needs in Housing", 1964 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Minutes, correspondence, notes
- Pennsylvania State University, Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  correspondence
- Penn State Evaluation, 1964-1964 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Reports, booklists, charts, faculty and graduate student lists, curriculum, department catalog
- Semi Annual Report No 4 and 5, Board meeting, 8 April, 1960 and 6 December 1960, Building Research Advisory Board, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Cornell Model Kitchen, 1953 (Box 4)
  91 Blueprints and pages of Bill of Material for Kitchen
- "Activity Patterns and Attitudes Toward Housing of Families Living in Specially Designed Apartments for Aged in 10 New York City Projects", by Johanna F. Alger with Glen H. Beyer, Cornell University Housing Research Center, 1959 (Box 4)
  2 Copies
- "Farmhouse Planning Guides - Household Activity Data and Space Needs Related to Design - Statistical Supplement", by Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station and others, 1959 (Box 4)
- "Marketing Handbook for the Pre-Fabricated Housing Industry", by Glenn H. Beyer and James W. Partner, Research Publication 2, Cornell University Housing Research Center, 1955 (Box 4)
- "The Changing Farm Housing Inventory", by Charles H. Elliot with Glenn H. Beyer, Bulletin 930, Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station, 1958 (Box 4)
- "Commuting Patterns of Industrial Workers" by Leonard P. Adams and Thomas W. Mackesey, Research Publication 1, Cornell University Housing Research Center, 1955 (Box 4)
- "Economic Aspects of Housing for the Aged", by Glenn H. Beyer, Research Report 4, Cornell University Center for Housing and Environmental Studies, 1961 (Box 4)
- Home Buying Study (I), 1959-1962 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Home Buying Study (II), 1957-1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Home Buying Study, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Reports, correspondence, rough drafts
- Home Buying Study Reports, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Reports, survey forms
- Architecture Faculty, 1957-1960 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Reports, memos, minutes, M.C. correspondence
- Residential Lighting Project, to July 1956, 1954-1956 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Correspondence, reports, research
- Public housing - Study in the high Cost of 1957 Account of 7228, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Interim report, progress reports, memos, correspondence, rough draft
- HHFA-1949 Research program, 1949-1950 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Checklist, news releases(HHFA), reference guide, charts
- Prefab - O2D Orders, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Book orders
- HRC - Lightolier Grant, 1954-1959 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  Memos, vouchers, ledger page
- Residential Lighting Project, July 1956 onwards, 1956-1959 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  Correspondence, reports, project outlines
- Housing Research Center - Press Releases Etc., 1950-1951, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- The changing Farmhouse Inventory Study, Elliott, December 1957, 1955-1958 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  Correspondence, study report (final and rough draft), notes, processing instructions, questionnaire
- Rural Housing Quality, Measurement of., 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  Questionnaire, report, correspondence
- Housing Research Center - CMA Research Residence, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  Contracts (drafts), correspondence
- Sectional Housing, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  Rough draft
- Indiana, Graduate School of. Savings and Loans, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  Correspondence, pamphlets
- Cornell Kitchen Film, 1955, 1956, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  T.S., M.S., carbon correspondence
- No 8 Patent and Copyright, 1952-1955, 1957, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  T.S., carbon correspondence, pamphlets, drawings
- Criteria for Kitchen Design From a Home Management Point of View, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  T.S. memo, M.C. report
- No 8 - Draft of Bulletin, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 21A-B)
  T.S. and M.C. draft, M.C. memos, drawings
- Kitchen - Technical, Volume II, 1955, 1954-56 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  M.C. questionnaires, T.S. carbon correspondence
- Building Research Advisory Board (BRAB), January 1965 onwards, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 1A-B)
  M.C. and T.S. Correspondence, research proposals, news releases, reports, agenda
- BRAB - HUD Advisory Committee, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Visual aid (speech presentation), charts, correspondence
- GRAB - Symposium on the Performance Concept in Building, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Symposium proceedings
- BRAB - Board Reports, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Agenda, reports to the board
- Building Research Advisory Board (BRAB), January 1964 - December 1964, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  M.C. and M.S. Correspondence, agenda, minutes, reports
- Building Research Institute Inc. (BRI), 1964-1966 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Minutes, M.C. correspondence, proceedings, directory
- National Research Council, 1959-1960 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  News, research reports, correspondence
- Union Carbide, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Building Science, Pergamon Press; Kiefer Manuscript - July 1964, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Correspondence, manuscript
- Pergamon Press, Building Science, Journal, 1963-1968 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Correspondence, magazine reprints
- Pergamon Press, Building Science, Journal (II), 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  Galley proof, page proofs, manuscript, periodical (AIA "Research News")
- "Future Oriented Research (Correspondence etc.)", 1968 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  T.S. and M.S. Correspondence, magazine clippings
- Housing and Home Finance Agency (Ashley et al.), 1959-1964 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  M.S. and T.S. Correspondence, M.C. reports, pamphlets, circulars, M.S. notes, magazine clippings
- Title VIII - Housing Act f 1964 (Urban), 1964, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  Carbons, M.C., P.C. and M.S. correspondence, memos, M.C. records and documents, P.C. and M.C. reports
- Extensions - Rural Area Development Program, 1962-1965 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  news bureau releases, carbons, M.C. correspondence, memos, M.S. notes, T.S. biography
- Bureau of Census - Correpondence, 1958-1960, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  T.S Carbon correspondence, M.C. tables and reports
- Housing Research Council, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  T.S. Carbon Correspondence
- Cornell Kitchen - Blue Prints, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  Blueprints
- Kitchen - Miscellaneous, Volume III, 1957, 1959-1960 (Box 6, Folder 19A-B)
  M.S. and T.S. carbon correspondence
- College and Inter-college Correspondence (Transfer), 1951, 1956 - 1962, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Carbon M.S. and T.S. correspondence, memos, reports, addresses, article, newsletter, directories, calendar
- College correspondence (Home Economy Only), January 1964 onwards, 1964-1967 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  T.S. and M.S. Communications, memos, reports, newsletters, directories, P.C. reports, questionnaire, M.S. inventory
- College and Inter-college Correspondence, 1957, 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Carbon M.S. and T.S. correspondence, memos, reports, addresses, article, newsletter, directories
- Advisory Committee on Housing for Senior Citizens, 1961-1968 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  P.C. forms, memos, M.S. correspondence, agendas, forms, newsletters, pamphlets, M.C. listings
- SSRC Committee on Social Science Research Center (II), 1964-1966 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  M.S. Correspondence, memos, listings, announcements, reports, draft, minutes, P.C. questionnaire
- International Institute of Housing Technology Member, Advisory Board - Fresno State College, July 1967 onwards, 1967, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  M.C. record, abstract, carbon T.S. correspondence, P.C. newsletters
- Study Committee on Educational Environment and University Faculty Commission on Student Affairs, 1960-1965 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  M.C. reports, questions, memos, minutes, study, drafts and registration; M.S. notes memos, correspondence; P.C. communications, statement and report; Dean's List, carbon reports, charts
- Faculty Student Housing Subcommittee, 1960, 1962-1964 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  M.C. reports, surveys, notices, P.C. correspondence
- Housing Research Council, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  M.C. communications, list
- "AAUP American Association of University Professors", 1963, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  Minutes, M.C. and T.S. correspondence
- Educational Policies Committee, 1961-1962 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- HD Department Staff Meetings, 1958, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  Carbons, M.C. memos
- Home Economy Guidelines Committee, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  Pamphlets, M.C. questions, memos, reports
- Human Ecology (Home Economy), Faculty Meetings and Notices, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  M.C. minutes
- International Home Economy Advisory Committee, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  T.S. carbon memos, M.C. minutes
- No 8 Field Study - Cornell Kitchen, 1953-55 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  T.S. carbon and M.S. correspondence, schedules, M.C. memos
- No 8 Cornell Kitchen Legal Agreements, 1953-1954 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  T.S. Carbon Agreements and Drafts
- No 8 Miscellaneous, 1952-1955 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  T.S. and carbon M.S. correspondence, M.C. agreement
- BRAB - Re: Hollomon and Sen. Rooney Correspondence, 1963, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 1A-D)
  T.S., M.C. and P.C. Correspondence, testimonies
- Building Research Institute Inc., thru December 1963, 1962, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 2A-C)
  M.C. Correspondence, memos, P.C. agreement
- Building research Advisory Board, July 1961 - December 1963, 1961-1963 (Box 8, Folder 3A-C)
- BRI - Liaison Committee, 1959-1961 (Box 8, Folder 4A-B)
  T.S. carbon, P.C. drafts, correspondence
- BRAB 1959 Annual Meeting, 1958, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  T.S., M.S. correspondence, M.C. report
- BRAB November 1958 Meeting, 1953, 1958, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  Carbons, M.C. correspondence, reports, pamphlets
- Building Research Institute, 1956, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  T.S. carbon correspondence, M.C. memos, announcements
- BRI Plastic Studies Group, 1957, 1958, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  M.C. memos, outlines, T.S carbon correspondence
- BRI - Installation and Maintainance of Resilient Smooth Surface Flooring, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  M.C. correspondence, questionnaire
- BRI Documentation Program, 1958-1960 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  T.S. memo and correspondence, M.C. speech, announcement, P.C. correspondence
- BRI Conference on Building Illumination, 1958, 1959, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  T.S. carbon, M.C. correspondence, M.C. reports, paper
- BRI Program Planning Committee, 1960, 1961, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  T.S. and M.C. correspondence, P.C. memo, M.C. reports, news clippings
- BRI Annual Reports and Anunal Meetings, 1957, 1958, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  M.C. annual reports, announcements, pamphlets
- BRI Membership, 1958, 1959, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  M.C. minutes, M.C and T.S. correspondence
- BRI. Education Liaison Committee, January 1961 onwards, 1960-1963 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  M.C. minutes, reports, T.S. and P.C. correspondence
- BRI Board of Governors, 1961, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  M.C. reports, carbon memos, M.C. agenda, T.S. memo, T.S. correspondence, P.C. list
- BRI Committee on Research (Formerly Committee for Coordinate Basic Residence), 1957-1959 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  M.C. Pamphlets, T.S. correspondence, drafts, memos, M.C. reports, memos
- BRI Committee on Research, January 1960 - December 1960, 1959, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 18A-B)
  M.C. drafts, reports, T.S. carbon correspondence
- "Architectural Research and Social Values", AIA-NSF Conference - Ann Arbor, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  T.S. carbon discussion paper
- Seminar 1960, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  T.S. carbon summary, exam, M.C. program
- Mr. Beyer - Seminar 1959, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  Carbon memo, M.C. programs, exam, news clippings
- 1958 Seminar, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  M.C. report, programs, proposal, news clippings, T.S. lists
- U.S. Senate Monograph Demand and Need Factors - U.S. From HS 1960 - 1970 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  Carbon report
- Human Problems and Building Trends, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  M.C. paper
- Technical Information Needs of the Social Science Researcher, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- "Practical Builder" (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Review of Activities, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  Carbon memo, draft, M.C. report
- National Housing Policy, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  Carbon M.S. and T.S. correspondence
- Farming Housing in the U.S., 1950 (Box 9, Folder 1950)
  T.S. outline, maps, pamphlets
- Field Observation in Housing Research, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Home Selection and Home Management (Box 9, Folder 13)
  M.S. notes, carbon T.S. reports
- Laundry-Sewing Center (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Kitchen Layout Studies, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 15A)
- Planning the Kitchen, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 15B)
- Our National Housing Policy, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  Carbon paper
- "Technical Information Needs of the Social Science Researcher" - Speech, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  M.C. paper, chart
- "The Cornell Kitchen" - Speech, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Influences of Socioeconomic Factors on House Design" - Speech, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- "Farm Housing in the Northeast" - Speech, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  M.C. talk
- "Housing Statistics", Compiled monthly from Government and Other Sources, Washington: Housing and Home Finance Agency, 1960, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  Pamphlet
- Americana - 1961, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  Carbon report, M.C. news releases, pamphlets
- Encyclopedia Americana, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  T.S. and carbon report, news clippings, pamphlet
- Americana Annual 1960, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Encyclopedia Americana 1956, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  T.S. and carbon report, article, pamphlet
- "World Book Encyclopedia", 1958 (Box 9, Folder 26)
- 1958 Americana Annual Article, 1957, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  Carbon M.C. reports, M.S. notes
- "Housing Statistics", Compiled monthly from Government and Other Sources, Washington: Housing and Home Finance Agency, 1960, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 28)
- Forecast Article, February 1960 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  Carbon article
- Collier's yearbook 1960, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  Carbon article, M.C. memo
- Collier Encyclopaedia Year Book 1958, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  M.C. memo, article
- Collier's Yearbook 1961 and 1962, 1960, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  T.S. and M.C. correspondence, carbon article
- Study of Housing Requirements and House Improvement Practices of Rural Families in Five Selected Areas of New York State, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  M.S. notes, M.C. studies
- Social Science Application to Housing Design, Owner's Schedule - Renter's Schedule (Box 9, Folder 34)
  M.C. study
- Study of Farm Housing Requirements in the Northeast Region, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  M.C. study and instructions
- Adjustment in Rural Housing Inventory due to Consolidation of Farms - Schedule A - Commercial Farms, Schedule B - Secondary Houses, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 36)
- A Marketing Study of the Pre-fabricated Housing Industry, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 37)
- Regional Basic Space Requirements of Farm Houses as Influenced by Activity Patterns (Box 9, Folder 38)
- Improved Housing Design Based on Family Living Characteristics - SIx County Study (Box 9, Folder 39)
- Improved Housing Design Based on Family Living Characteristics - Binghamton, 1955, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  M.C. study, report
- HRC Correspondence, Re: Liability, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  M.C. correspondence
- Strange Space Tips (Box 9, Folder 42)
  M.C. pamphlets
- Management and Family Living, 1951, 1952, 1955, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 43)
- Articles and Clippings, 1948, 1950, 1952, 1953, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  magazine articles, news clippings
- Housing Research, 1957, 1959, 1963, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 45A-C)
  M.C. reports and papers
- Measuring Housing Quality, 1948, 1950, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  M.C. reports, surveys
- Housing Research Center, Information on Housing-related Books and Publications, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  Loose leaf informational notebook
- Indiana School, Meeting of American Finance Association, 29 December 1959, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  T.S. correspondence, M.C. papers
- Housing and Suburbia, 2nd Session, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  T.S. discussion, M.C. papers
- 'Design and Liability Factors: "personal" Values', 4th Session, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 50)
- "Future Trends and Problems", 5th Session, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 51)
- "Research in Housing", 5th Session - Indiana, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  M.S. notes, T.S. introduction, M.C. paper
- "Design and Standards", 4th Session - Indiana (Box 9, Folder 53)
  M.S. and T.S. notes, talk
- "housing Supply", 2nd Session - Indiana, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  M.S. and T.S. notes, article, news clipping, M.C. census
- "Housing Demand", 1st Session - Indiana (Box 9, Folder 55)
  M.S. notes, T.S. outlines
- "Home Ownership and Financing", 3rd Session - Indiana (Box 9, Folder 56)
  M.S. notes
- "Current Home Building and financing Situation", 1st Session (Box 9, Folder 57)
  M.S. and T.S. notes
- Housing and Economic Profiles of the Elderly", 3rd Session, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 58)
- CHRES (HRC) Correspondence, 1963 - 1964, #3, 1963, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 1A-B)
  T.S. carbon, M.C. correspondence, M.C. proposal, memo, report
- Housing Research Center, 1960-1963, 1957, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  Correspondence, memo, carbon drafts, M.C. proposal